てめぇの　あの技には
All I'm doing is furthering the old man's will.
２つ　デッケェ弱点がある！
I'm not looking for any trouble. Ging-san, why do this if you don't want
ついに　ナックルに 本気の戦いを挑んだゴン
Request x And x Wish
ゴンの技に弱点があると 指摘したのだった ところで　ゴン。 ん？ あの技の名前 何て言うんだ？　こら。
On August 8th at 12:00 AM, in the Hunter Association main headquarters, the voting to elect Netero's successor, Heart Is Valuable the 13th Chairman, began.
しまった！
The rules set by Ging
技の名前　ちゃんと 決めてなかった気がする
made all of the six hundred and sixty-one members
ジャ…　ジャンケン！
both a candidate and voter.
うわ　そのままだ。 ぐっ！ 「ジャジャン拳」か　なるほどな。
On this day, voter turnout was below the required 95%, meaning the vote had to be redone.
ジャンケンと必殺技を
1) Pariston
2) Cheadle
3) Ickshonpe
4) Botobai
ジャジャンと出すみたいな 効果音とを掛けてるわけだ。
However, the second vote Election for the 13th Chairman
1) Pariston — 251 (37.9%)
2) Cheadle — 46
3) Ickshonpe — 28
4) Botobai — 27
5) Mizaistom — 24
あっ…　いや…。
8) Cutie, Sanbica,
Teradein, Bushidora — 10
12) Loupe — 9
13) Linne, Biscuit — 8
15) Tsezguerra — 7
16) Knov, Kanzai — 6
18) Kite, Satotz — 4
20) Menchi, Geru, 13 others — 3
35) Saiyu, 11 others — 2
47) Gon, Hanzo, 16 others — 1 also failed to meet the requirements, Vote must be retaken because
requirements were not met.
最初の「ジャ」は つっかえただけなんだけど
Invalid — 45                    Absent — 33
Turnout — 88.2% and had to be redone again.
なかなか　いい名前じゃねえか！ こら！
Taking the results from the
two votes into consideration... First, we will have Beans-san review all ballots
あっ　うん まぁ　いいや　それで。 いいのかよ!?
before they are entered, to reduce
the number of invalid votes.
ゴン！ てめぇの「ジャジャン拳」には ２つ　デケェ弱点がある！
Second, Hunters who violate the rules by
abstaining or submitting invalid votes
１つ！　溜めが長ぇ！
will have their licenses temporarily taken away.
戦闘中に 技を出すまでの数秒間ってのは
Those are my two suggestions.
気が遠くなるほど長ぇぜ。
If we implement the first,
do we still need the second?
そう簡単に 出せると思うなよ　こら。 分かってる。
Just getting rid of the invalid
votes would put us over 95%.
２つ！　危険がデケェ！
I wouldn't be so sure...
威力を上げようとして
Some Hunters may play hooky when they
learn they can't submit invalid votes.
拳にオーラを 集めりゃ集めるほど 体を守るオーラが減るだろうが！
There are those who would trample
on the former chairman's wishes. What?
もろいとこ攻撃されたら イチコロだろうが　ボケ!!
Drop it. You'll only waste time.
リスクは　承知の上さ！
Oh? Did I say something wrong?
それを補うために　この１か月間 修行して来たんだ!!
The former chairman declared that
a 95% turnout was required, so Hunters who submit invalid votes or
won't vote are betraying his memory.
あらめて見ると すげぇオーラだぜ
They just don't want to see you become chairman!
総量だけでいったら プロの中堅クラスと遜色ねえ
Then they should vote for someone else.
惜しいな…
I'm sure there are other qualified candidates.
経験が足りねえ！
Is that too hard for you, with your limited
vocabulary and math skills?
実践が少ねえ！
I told you that you'd only waste time.
思いっ切りの良さは　半端ねえ 死線は　何度か乗り越えてるし
Before adding new rules,
I believe we should broadcast
天性のもんもあるだろう
each candidate's message.
だが　ぎこちねえ
Besides, abstaining and submitting invalid
votes are not technically violations.
オーラの流れが　ぎこちねえ！
I fully agree with your first statement, but the second makes me
wonder if I heard right...
おめぇが どこを守ろうとしているのか
I cannot believe those words came from one
これから 何をしようとしているのか
of the former chairman's leading supporters.
オーラの動きで 全部　分かっちまう!!
The former chairman said that the difficulty of this election was D-rank.
うっ！ それを逆手にとって 少しフェイントを入れて！
Which means, for us Hunters with stars,
this should be a simple task.
打撃ポイントをずらせば…
In other words, the former chairman
trusted us to handle this. Pariston, you're a pain!
うっ…！
Don't talk! Keep your mouth shut!
ガハっ！ あうっ！ ガハっ！
The difficulty level is just his way of
expressing his degree of trust in the Zodiacs.
こうなる！
If it's F, he's challenging us.
ハァ　ハァ…。 クソっ！
You can spin it however you want, but abstaining and submitting invalid
votes don't violate any rules, scumbag.
完全に読まれてる オーラの流れ！
When I called them violations...
やっぱりだ　ナックルは…
I was only insinuating that those
Hunters are mistaken in their manner of paying respects to the former chairman.
さてと　そろそろ 全力で　ぶち込むぜ。
The message is that making the election
a success would be the right way to pay our respects to him. Then, say that during your speech!
何て…
If you make it a rule, that's coercion!
死んでも恨むなよ　こら！ 何て　優しいんだ！
Is coercion such a bad thing?
)
Okay, I get the idea...
That's enough.
)
I'm fine with both suggestions.
言われなければ 秒殺だったかもしれない。 )
My reasons are different than yours, but I agree that, barring
extraordinary circumstances, no Hunters should be abstaining
or submitting invalid votes.
そして　導いてくれてる
First things first. I hope you aren't going to say that,
during that time, Hunters who
どうすれば　より強くなれるか
have their licenses taken away
aren't considered pro Hunters.
優し過ぎるよ！
You aren't that stupid, are you?
最初は　グ！
I wouldn't think of using such underhanded
logic to manipulate the vote.
くっ…。
Their licenses will be confiscated. Nothing more.
Uh...
やらせねえって 言っただろうが！
Are you saying that someone
ナメんなよ　こら！
would use the threat of a license going
missing to manipulate the vote?
今のが　全力？
We can't guarantee no one will do that.
ん？ ナメてるのは　どっちだ！
Let this be clearly recorded in the minutes...
真剣勝負だろ！
Hunters who lose their licenses during the election
殺す気で来い　ナックル！
will not lose their right to vote.
くっ…。 最初は　グ！
That way, no one can manipulate
the turnout or the majority.
行くぞ！ ジャン！
I hate to admit it, but unless we do something about
the majority, not just the turnout, Pariston will keep smiling.
おりゃ！
He already seems to have secured the votes
こっちだ！ うおっ！
that went to Ginta, Piyon, and Cluck.
くっ！ ハッ！ どはっ！ 最初は　グ
If our timing is wrong, there will be casualties.
ジャン！
I hate to admit it...
この野郎　「ジャジャン拳」を フェイントに使いやがった 技をつぶしてやるって感じが 見え見えだったよ。
A beast that cannot be tamed... Why did the Chairman select
him as Vice Chairman?
「ジャジャン拳」の弱点を 逆手にとった 敵の心理を利用した作戦だ
Since I get to choose my second-in-command, choosing a yes-man wouldn't be any fun.
ナックルにとって ゴンの「ジャジャン拳」は　いわば 狙い球の一つ　見逃し厳禁
It should be someone I can't stand...
打ち返さなければならない ど真ん中の絶好球
That is who I want at my side.
それが力みとなる 来たと思う瞬間 余計な力が入る 打てる　打たねば
Chairman, I still believe you made a mistake.
それは　オーラでも 同じことが言える
Young Killua has returned?
術者が意図して抑えなければ オーラは　力んだ箇所へ集まり
That's great...
打とうとする瞬間 さらに大きくなる
When I saw his name on the list of Hunters
who didn't vote, I was worried.
術者が未熟なら　あるいは 平常心を失っていれば
How's he doing?
)
He's opened Testing Gates 1 through 5?
ゴンは　ナックルの甘さを指摘し 動揺を誘った
Actually, his expression was what concerned me.
結果　フェイントは見事　成功
He looked very distressed...
恐らく　この作戦は
I couldn't bring myself to speak to him.
「ジャジャン拳」の威力を 知っている者ほど効果がある ゴンが技を出そうとする瞬間 技の破壊力を知っている者ほど
If you run into his friend there,
can you relay a message?
「来る！」という恐怖心が 自身の平常心を削る
Ask him to help young Killua. Well...
フェイントも より効果が高まり
His friend is why he's upset.
敵が退けば　「チー」や「パー」での 追い打ちが仕掛けやすくなる
What? Gon-kun?
使いにくい技だと思っていた それが弱点だと…
Young Killua...
ゴンは　考えていたのか？ 弱点の克服法を
Let me see Alluka. I need her power.
いや
I don't have time, Dad!
思いついたんだ この戦いの中で！
I'll go even if you try to stop me, so come with me. It's useless.
成長する　ものすごい速さで
No one can control Alluka.
戦いの中で！
That's wrong!
ハァ　ハァ…。
You're wrong... Brother's wrong... Alluka's a member of the family!
早くも　「堅」を維持するのが しんどくなって来たぞ まだ２０分も 戦ってないはずなのに
She isn't a machine! As her brother, I'm asking her for help!
動いたりしながらだから 消耗が激しいんだ
For help?
修行での１時間が 実戦では１０分だとすると…
That child
あと１０分足らずしか 「堅」は持たない
is not human. You shouldn't consider
オーラでの攻防力が下がれば 負けは確実
that thing to be a member of the family.
その前に決める
What did you say?
来いや！
That thing
なのに　ナックルは　まだ 余力を十分残し
Sit.
「ジャジャン拳」は 発動準備の段階で 大量のオーラを必要とする フェイントだけでも　相当のオーラが 消費されているはず
If someone tries to dispel the restriction
and covenant Gon set for himself, they'll be either repelled or killed.
すでに　ゴンは 技を３回起動させている
If Alluka hasn't changed, I'm the only one who can help her.
戦ってから ２０分が経過してる もう一度　「ジャジャン拳」を 使おうとしたら あと１２分あるか　ないか
And Alluka's the only one who can save Gon.
それが全力で戦える限界
Promise me one thing.
ハァ　ハァ…。
If I ignore a friend I have the ability to help,
wouldn't I be betraying him?
ゴン　俺に全力を出せとか ぬかしたが
Come with me.
放出系の攻撃か それにしても　「グー」に比べたら 低レベル
I'm sure you already know this, but no new requests have been made.
根っからの強化系だな おめぇは
Who made the last wish?
放出系の「パー」は 明らかにパワーダウン
Milluki.
スピードもねえ　威力もねえ
He asked for the newest computer
available at the time.
この程度のレベルなら 球に仕掛けがあるはずもねえ
He made the wish himself in Alluka's
presence, so he couldn't lie.
はじき返して　しまいだ！ うりゃ！
A computer shouldn't be that bad...
あいこで…！ あいこ!?
Was it because Illumi was controlling me?
球を目隠しに使い　背後へ… ヤベェ！ 「ジャジャン拳」の連続攻撃！
How could I leave my little
sister in this situation?
グ!!
Killua, I want to go over this again.
うわ!!
When making a wish to Alluka,
what are the rules?
んっ　おぉ…。 ん？
Killua, if you can't stay calm, we're stopping now.
「グー」の前に　すでに オーラを使い果たしていたのか
Can you go over the rules for me?
そうでなけりゃ　倒されていた
Alluka is...
どこ行くんだよ　こら！
Yes, yes... I will!
帰るんだよ。
There!
おめぇは　やんねえのか？
Climb the stairs!
俺は余裕だぜ。
Yes, yes.
あんたはゴンが　また明日 相手になる。
Raise me up high! Yes, yes.
きっと　今日みたいなわけには いかないぜ。
There you go! Mitsuba...
俺は　シュートを倒す。
Yes, yes? What is it, Master Alluka?
ホントにやれんの？ ったりめぇだ！　こら！
Yes... Master Alluka's
face suddenly changed!
明日さ…。 あ？
Yeah, it's okay. I can handle this.
あんたが勝つならいいよ 全力じゃなくても。
Alluka, lift me up high!
でも　もし　あんたが 力を出し切らずに負けたら
'Kay. Up high...
許さねえ。
Up high...
あんたを一生　許さねえからな。
'Kay. See? She's back. Keep this a secret from everyone.
相変わらず甘いな　お前は。
It happens after three requests are fulfilled...
敵に塩を送りまくって どうするんだ。
Yep, her eyes turn black.
果ては　相手にまで それを非難される始末。 ＮＧＬに行く気がないなら
And they turn back after Alluka lifts you up high? No, then Alluka grants a wish.
さっさと割り符を 彼らに渡したらどうだ？
I didn't understand at first...
まぁ　あの２人は 受け取らないだろうがね。 てめぇ…。
So I wished for her to tell me
how to turn her eyes back, and Alluka told me.
テンパってねえ時は マジで偉そうだな　ったくよう。 てめぇが この１か月でやったことといや
Do you remember the exact words Alluka said?
尾行だけだろうが　こら！
After she grants a wish, her eyes turn white.
やるよ　明日は　俺も戦う。
And when three of her requests
are fulfilled, they turn black.
安心しな　万全な体調で 明日　戦えるように
No matter how small they are. Yes, I understand.
マッサージしておいたわさ。
Mitsuba... Carry me!
それより 問題は　キルアだわよ
I can't do that, Master.
この１か月間　全く敵と 戦えなかったのは　計算外
Then, Mitsuba, shake my hand.
キルア！
Oh, um... I can't do that, Master.
勝負よ　私と！
Then I want a piggyback ride, Mitsuba.
えっ!?
What should I do?
どうしたの!? キルア　その顔！
Come on, Master! Let's go catch some bugs. Okay?
ん？　特訓だよ　ビスケとの。
Then, Mitsuba, lift me up high.
特訓？　リンチじゃなくて？ それより　お前のほうは大丈夫かよ 体調は。
I can't do that, either, Mast—
はぁ…　危ねえ　危ねえ。 ん？
Mitsuba was in the play area...
((いいこと？ 昨日のことを喋ったら
Hasamu was in the butlers' quarters.
顔が　さらに その３倍になるわよさ！)) ) ありゃ　本気だった。
So two people, in different locations, were instantly crushed at the same time...
((分かったかい？ あんたの弱点))
What is happening? It's because she refused.
) )
She refused four of Alluka's requests.
((戦闘に関して慎重過ぎる
Yasuha, piggyback ride!
あるいは　己を過小評価していると 言い換えてもいい))
Yes, Master.
((先に言っとくけど それは　あんたのせいじゃ　ない))
Master Alluka...
((あんたに 戦闘を教え込んだ人物の責任))
Can you make me a millionaire?
((戦闘力ってのは 環境　体調などで上下するもの))
There has been a mysterious incident
in which an airship transporting money
((例えば　Ｃが絶好調なら 不調時のＤに 高確率で勝てるだろう))
suddenly went missing, and when it
was found, all the money was gone.
((つまり　条件を整えれば Ａ　Ｂ　Ｃの誰もが
The pilot and crew members have
provided baffling explanations.
Ｄに勝てる潜在力を 持っているわけだわさ))
It will take a while to determine the cause.
((それに対し　あんたの場合
I'm very sorry!
敵のマックスを測ろうとする))
I couldn't help myself...
((そして　常に 最悪の場合を想定して戦う))
I find it hard to believe that
this was just a coincidence.
((互角の力量を持つ敵とでも 「かなり強い」とか
When Alluka is with us... He never makes any requests.
「敵に　こうされたらヤバい」とか 考えちゃってる)) ((相手が少しでも格上ならば もうＮＧ))
Dad, can you let me choose the next butler?
((「何とか勝とう」って気持は びた一文なくなる))
So your mission is to fulfill Alluka's requests.
((選択は　逃げの一手 負け犬の思考))
Yes... I understand.
((あんたは　これから その悪癖を押さえ込み 自分よりも強い敵に 真っ向勝負を挑む
If you clear this mission,
I will spare you and your lover.
意志の力が必要になる))
Hey, Kasuga...
((もしも明日 シュートを倒せなければ
Yes, what is it? Give me your liver.
ゴンの元から消えなさい))
Um, that's not... You know? You won't do it?
よし！　今度こそ　勝つぞ！
Then, Kasuga, give me your duodenum. Please wait, Master...
フン　フン　フン！
Let's play a different game! Okay?
過保護とも思えるような 戦闘育成法は
Give me your brain.
恐らく　キルアに対する 過剰な愛から来ている
When three of Alluka's requests are
fulfilled, she'll grant one wish.
いびつで利己的な ゆがんだ愛 それだけに　強く　重く 非対象者に絡みつく
There probably isn't any limit
to the wishes she can grant.
その呪縛 並大抵の努力では解けない
My guess is that she can grant any wish. Wish But the bigger the wish she grants...
私にも分からない
And the sacrifice isn't made by the
one whose wish was granted.
どう　決着がつくか
It's the next person who fulfills the requests. Request 1                             Request 2